Guide to the Paul Jones Chapman papers, 1940-1983
Chapman, Paul Jones papers, 1940-1983
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Paul Jones Chapman papers, 1940-1983.
22-1-2102
P. J. (Paul Jones) Chapman, 1900-.
1.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence and research materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence concerning the graduate program of the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva, 1940-1983; selection of a head for the Entomology Department at Cornell University, 1965; and Rachel Carson's SILENT SPRING, 1962-1963. Also, research material concerning SILENT SPRING.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence concerning the graduate program of the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva, 1940-1983; selection of a head for the Entomology Department at Cornell University, 1965; and Rachel Carson's SILENT SPRING, 1962-1963. Also, research material concerning SILENT SPRING.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Chapman, P. J. (Paul Jones), 1900- .; Carson, Rachel, 1907-1964.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Graduate students.; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.; New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Entomology.
Subjects:
Entomology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Related collection:Geneva Experiment Station Project. Oral History Interview with Paul Chapman, #13\6\944, trsc.3888.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Materials on Rachel Carson's Silent Spring
Box 1 folders1-5
Series II. Correspondence
Box 1 folders 6-15
Series III. Administrative-Miscellaneous
Box 1 folders 16-18
Series IV. National Science Foundation Grants
Box 1 folders 19-23
Series V. Annual Review Articles
Box 1 folders 24-29
Series VI. Articles, Papers, etc.
Box 1 folders 30-49 Box 2 folders 1-16
Series VII. Station History Publication
Box 2 folders 17-30
Series VIII. Photo Album- "P. J. Chapman, The First 68 Years"
Box 3
Series IX. Publications
Box 4 folders 1-3; 15
Series X. Correspondence
Box 4 folders 4-13
Series XI. Oral History Interviews. Personal
Box 4 folders 11
Series XII. Photographs
Box 4 folders 12-14
Series XIII. Subject Files
Box 4 folders 16-31
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Materials on Rachel Carson's Silent Spring
  - Literature (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Publications (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Agricultural Chemical Association (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Studies and Reports (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, etc., 1926-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ESA, Comstock Hall Dedication Miscellaneous Correspondence, Paul. J Chapman, Edward H. Glass (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Corn Ear Worm Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publications, Letters (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Dr. Ralph W. Dean, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dean Charles E. Palm, October 10, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Professor Jose M. del Rivero, Universidad Polititecnica, Valencia, Spain (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - R. D. O'Brien, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Tressler-AVI Publishing Company, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Research Grants, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III. Administrative, Miscellaneous
  - Statements on Work in Progress, etc. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alvin J. Braun, Department of Plant Pathology (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Geneva Station's Involvement in the Graduate Training Program, 1940-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series IV. National Science Foundation Grants
  - Correspondence, 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NSF Grant, G-22240, April 1, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NSF Grant Application for G-22240, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Refund for sale of "Tortricid" Book (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Extension Request for G-22240, September 15, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series V. Annual Review Articles
  - Australia and New Zealand (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - USSR and Sinkiang, China (Far East) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - South America (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - South Africa, Entomology Review Articles (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - USSR- Europa Caucasus, Tashkent and Alma Ata (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Japan, Entomology Review Articles (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series VI. Articles, Papers, etc.
  - Competition, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Seed Treatment for the Control of fungus Diseases and the Seed Corn Maggot, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Should Chemists Conducting Chemical Research in the Entomology Field Be Assigned to a Chemistry or Entomology Division?", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Selection of Successor as Head of Entomology Department, Geneva, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Publications on Apple Insects (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Apple Crataegus, Ecology Notes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Apple Feeder-Collecting Sites (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - European and Mediterranean Plant Protection (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Psocid Taxonomy Collection (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sparganothis idarusalis Biglerville, PA Culture, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Checklist of Apple Feeders, "Lepidoptera" (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Dr. Dean's Manuscript on Codling Moth, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The European Chafer-Glasgow and Later Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The European Chafer, 1942-1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - The European Chafer-Reports, Authorized Control Measures (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The European Chafer Conference, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Insecticide-Fungicide Conference, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Japanese Beet (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Dr. Marvin Harris, Materials on Pecans (Carya) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - The Problems Encountered in Dividing Up the Field of Plant Agriculture Between Cornell's Two Agricultural Experiment Stations, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Seeds (Harmon) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Seeds and Vegetable Sciences, Chapter XVI (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History of Pomology for Indianapolis, Roger Way, pp. 1-57 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, Photograph of Army Commission (1922) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Student Fellowship ("Station Notes"), October 25, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Heinicke - Party (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - P. J. Parrott - Obituaries (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Victor Hunt Lowe, 1869-1903 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Derrill M. Daniel, WWII-Retirement Record (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Arthur J. Heinicke (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Retirement, Letter from Lydia J. Gamball, June 14, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Chapman House, June 27, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Flight Periods of the Larger Species of Moths (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - George J. Hucker, Obituaries, Statements, May 19, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Obituary, Notices (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Siegfried E. Lienk, Memorial Statement from E. H. Glass (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series VII. Station History Publication
  - Substation Histories (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Drafts of Station History (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Professor Ed Smith, Final Draft, History of the Entomological Society of America (ESA) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A Brief History of the ASE, etc. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Working Relationship Between NYSAES at Geneva and Research Programs on Cornell Campus, Ithaca-Tony Shelton (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - History of New York State Agricultural Experiment Station (NYSAES), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Drafts for Hatch Act Centennial; Centennial of NYSAES; Department of Entomology (Geneva and Ithaca) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - History of Parrott Hall and the Octogon House; Gov. Flowers Visits Geneva; Geneva Historical Society and Museum (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Station History, Contributor File (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Station History, Misc. Writing by Chapman, Glass and Krauss (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Early and Late Drafts of Chapman's Early Chapters (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Early Notes on Organization of Station History (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Transcription of E. H. Glass Seminar Presented June 24, 1982, June 24, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Entomology at Geneva Experiment Station, 1903-1938 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Series VIII: Photo Album "P. J. Chapman, The First 68 Years" (Box 3)
- Series IX. Publications
  - Articles - Written by Chapman, 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings about Chapman, 1929-1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Biographical information and Photographs, 1939-1990s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publications on Oil Sprays (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series X. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1920s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence concerning Chief of Research at Geneva, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from A.M. Boyce, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from C.S. Koehler, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series XI. Oral History Interviews, Personal
  - Oral History Interviews by Gould F. Colman, Sept. 3, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series XII. Photographs
  - Photos - Arial (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photos - of Plants (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Photos - Wild Apple Trees (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series XIII. Subject Files
  - Carl Peterson Memorial Fund, Geneva Rotary Club (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Entomological Society of America (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - European Red Mite, Field Tests, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Extension Service Leaflets, CUAES, Dept. of Pathology (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Fruit Slides (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Geneva Rotary Club (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Green Fruit Worm, Literature (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Growth Stages in Fruit - Prints made by Howie Lyons, Dept. of Plant Pathology at Ithaca, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Integrated Pest Management, 1967, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Japan Print Matter (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - New York Census for 1875 (Number of Apple Trees) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - New York Crop Reporting Service (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Statistical Summary, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Spray Schedules, 1932, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Tortricid Fauna of Apple in New York (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Vegetable Research (Box 4, Folder 31)